Guide to the Marvin H. Pope Papers
Yale University Divinity School Library
- Published Articles and Reviews, 1947-1992, n.d.; Series III
  - "The Saltier of Atargatis Reconsidered", 1970 (Box 14P, Folder 331)
  - "A Mare in Pharaoh's Chariotry", 1970 (Box 14P, Folder 332)
  - "A Description of Baal", 1971 (Box 14P, Folder 333)
  - " A Description of Baal", 1971 (Box 14P, Folder 334)
  - "The Scene on the Drinking Mug from Ugarit", 1971 (Box 14P, Folder 335)
  - "Of Locusts and Locust Eggs" (correction), 1974 (Box 14P, Folder 337)
  - "The Story of Decipherment", 1975 (Box 14P, Folder 338)
  - "Song of Songs Notes", 1977 (Box 14P, Folder 339)
  - "Notes on the Rephaim Texts from Ugarit", 1977 (Box 14P, Folder 340)
  - "A Little Soul-Searching", 1978 (Box 14P, Folder 341)
  - "Mid Rock and Scrub, A Ugaritic Parallel to Exodus 7:19", 1978 (Box 14P, Folder 342)
  - "Response to Sasson on the Sublime Song", 1979 (Box 14P, Folder 343)
  - "Ups and Downs in El's Amours", 1979 (Box 14P, Folder 344)
  - "Some Early West Semitic Prayer Formulae", 1979 (Box 14P, Folder 345)
  - "Millar Burrows:1889-1980, In Memoriam", 1981 (Box 15P, Folder 346)
  - "An Arabic Cognate for Ugariticd BRLT?", 1981 (Box 15P, Folder 347)
  - " The Cult of the Dead at Ugarit", 1981 (Box 15P, Folder 348)
  - "Ugarit Poems Tell of Life and Death", 1986 Jan (Box 15P, Folder 349)
  - "The Timing of the Snagging of the Ram, Gen 22:13", 1986 June (Box 15P, Folder 350)
  - "Metastates in Canonical Shapes of the Super Song", 1988 (Box 15P, Folder 351)
  - "Vestiges of the Vocative Lamedh in the Bible", 1988 (Box 15P, Folder 352)
  - "Hosanna", 1988 April (Box 15P, Folder 353)
  - "Hosanna May Not Be What People Assume", n.d. (Box 15P, Folder 354)
  - "Reminiscence of David Noel Freedman", 1989 (Box 15P, Folder 355)
  - "A Re-Survey of Some Ugaritic-Hebrew Connections", 1991 (Box 15P, Folder 356)
  - lists of reviews of Pope's published work, n.d. (Box 15P, Folder 357)
  - reviews by others: "El in the Ugaritic Texts," author?, 1955 (Box 15P, Folder 358)
  - reviews by others: "El in the Ugaritic Texts," review by Ullendorf, 1956 (Box 15P, Folder 359)
  - reviews by others: "El in the Ugaritic Texts," reviews by Kapelrud, Eissfeldt, Salvoni, Ullendorf, Driver and Elliott, 1956 (Box 15P, Folder 360)
  - reviews by others: "El in the Ugaritic Texts," reviews by W.F. Albright, DeVaux, Rene Dussard, and Stanislav Segert, 1957 (Box 15P, Folder 361)
  - reviews of Pope's commentary on SOS, 1977-1979 (Box 15P, Folder 362)
  - review by W.F. Stinespring of Pope's commentary on SOS, 1979 (Box 15P, Folder 363)
  - reviews by others: "Unlocking the Poetry of Love in the Song of Songs" by Jack M. Sasson; "The Commentary of Commentaries"; "Song of Songs", 1978-1985 (Box 15P, Folder 364)
  - reviews by others: "Sex According to the Song of Songs" by Hyam Maccoby", 1979 June (Box 15P, Folder 365)
  - introduction by Mark Smith to a collection of Pope's essays, n.d. (Box 15P, Folder 366)
  - Published Reviews by Pope
    - "The Linguistic and Literary Form of the Book of Ruth", 1955 (Box 15P, Folder 367)
    - "Old Testament Dissertations, 1928-1958," compiled by Martin J. Buss (Box 15P, Folder 368)
    - "The Goddess Anath: Canaanite Epics of the Patriarchal Age" by Umberto Cassuto, 1951 (Box 15P, Folder 369)
    - "The Goddess Anath: Canaanite Epics of the Patriarchal Age" by Umberto Cassuto, 1951 (Box 15P, Folder 370)
    - "The Goddess Anath: Canaanite Epics of the Partiarchal Age" by Umberto Cassuto, 1951 (Box 15P, Folder 371)
    - "Apocryphal Scrolls Belonging to the Hebrew University" by E. L. Sukenik, 1955 (Box 15P, Folder 373)
    - "The Linguistic and Literary Form of the Book of Ruth;" "La Sainte Bible"; "Adam to Daniel: An Illustrated Guide to the Old Testament and Its Background", 1955, 1956, 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 374)
    - "La Sainte Bible", 1956 (Box 15P, Folder 375)
    - "Mission de Ras Shamra Tome VII" by C. Virolleaud, 1957 (Box 15P, Folder 376)
    - "Mission de Ras Shamra Tome VII"; "Le Palais Royal D'Ugarit II" and a note from W. F. Albright pointing out a mistake Pope made in his review, 1957 (Box 15P, Folder 377)
    - "Il Semitico di Nord-Ovest"; "Old Testament Dissertations 1928-1958"; "Marriage and Family Life in Ugaritic Literature", various dates (Box 15P, Folder 378)
    - "Mythologies of the Ancient World"; "The New Bible Dictionary"; "Studies and Essays in Honor of Abraham A. Neuman", various dates (Box 15P, Folder 379)
    - "Die Texte vom Toten Meer. Erste deutsche Gesamtubertragung"; "Linguistica Semitica; Presente e Futuro"; "An Introductory Hebrew Grammar"; "Hebrew Union College Annual: Vol. 32", various dates (Box 15P, Folder 380)
    - "Ancient Israel: Its Life and Institutions" by Roland de Vaux, 1960s (Box 15P, Folder 381)
    - " Seventh Day Adventist Bible Dictionary", n.d. (Box 15P, Folder 382)
    - ""Die Texte vom Toten Meer. Erste deutsche Gesamtubertragung"; "Seventh DAy Adventist Bible Dictionary"; "A Guide to the Bible", 1960 (Box 15P, Folder 383)
    - "Die Texte vom Totem Meer. Erste deutsche Gesamtubertragung" by Johann Maier, 1960 (Box 15P, Folder 384)
    - "How the Hebrew Language Grew"; "The Scroll of the War of the Sons of Light Against the Sons of Darkness", 1960, 1962 (Box 15P, Folder 385)
    - "The Bible and the Ancient Near East: Essays in Honor of William Foxwell Albright", 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 386)
    - ""Il Semitico di Nord-Ovest" by Giovanni Garbini, 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 387)
    - "Die Texte vom Toten Meer. Erste deutsche Gesamtubertragung" by Johann Maier, 1960 (Box 15P, Folder 388)
    - "Linguistica Semitica: Presente e Futuro" by Levi Della Vida, 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 389)
    - ""Biblical Archaeology"; "Adam to Daniel: An Illustrated Guide to the Old Testament and Its Background;" Sacra Pagina"; "New Directions in Biblical Thought", various dates (Box 15P, Folder 390)
    - "The Documentary Hypothesis" by Umberto Cassuto, 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 391)
    - ""Mythologies of the Ancient World," ed. by Samuel Noah Kramer, 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 392)
    - " The Bible and Ancient Near East: Essays in Honor of W.F. Albright", 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 393)
    - " Hebrew College Annual: Vol. 32," ed. by Elias L. Epstein, 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 394)
    - " Hommage A Wilhelm Vischer", 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 395)
    - ""Mission de Ras Shamra", 1961 (Box 15P, Folder 396)
    - "Ancient Israel" by Roland de Vaux (Box 15P, Folder 397)
    - "The Scroll of the War of the Sons of Light Against the Sons of Darkness," ed. by Yigael Yagin, 1962 (Box 15P, Folder 398)
    - "Hebrew Union College Annual Vol. 33," ed. Elias L. Epstein, 1962 (Box 15P, Folder 399)
    - "An Introductory Hebrew Grammar" by A.B. Davidson, 1962 (Box 15P, Folder 400)
    - "Before the Bible. The Common Background of Greek and Hebrew Civilizations" by Cyrus H. Gordon, 1963 (Box 15P, Folder 401)
    - "Hebrew and Semitic Studies", 1963 (Box 15P, Folder 402)
    - "The Art of Warfare in Biblical Lands in the Light of Archaeological Study", 1963 (Box 15P, Folder 403)
    - "An Introductory Hebrew Grammar" by A.B. Davidson, 1962 (Box 16P, Folder 404)
    - "Essays in Honor of Abraham A. Neuman", 1962 (Box 16P, Folder 405)
    - "The New Bible Dictionary", 1962 (Box 16P, Folder 406)
    - "Grammar of Palestinian Jewish Aramaic", 1962 (Box 16P, Folder 407)
    - "The Work of Pere Lagrange", 1963 (Box 16P, Folder 408)
    - "Testimonium Linguae: Participial Constructions in the Synoptic Gospels", 1963 (Box 16P, Folder 409)
    - "Gotteswort un menschliche Erfahrung", 1963 (Box 16P, Folder 410)
    - "Promise and Fulfilment: Essays Presented to Professor S.H. Hooke in Celebration of His Ninetieth Birthday", 1963 (Box 16P, Folder 411)
    - "The Ras Shamra Discoveries and the OId Testament" by Arvid S. Kapelrud, 1963 (Box 16P, Folder 412)
    - "In the Time of Harvest: Essays in Honor of Abba Hillel Silver on the Occasion of His 70th Birthday," ed. by Daniel Jeremy Silver, 1963 (Box 16P, Folder 413)
    - "Before the Bible. The Common Background of Greek and Hebrew Civilizations" by Cyrus H. Gordon, 1963 (Box 16P, Folder 414)
    - "From Moses to Qumran" by H. H. Rowley, 1964 (Box 16P, Folder 415)
    - "The Canaanites" by John Gray, 1964 (Box 16P, Folder 416)
    - "History, Archaeology, and Christian Humanism" by W.F. Albright, 1964 (Box 16P, Folder 417)
    - "The Legacy of Canaan" by John Gray, 1966 (Box 16P, Folder 418)
    - "The Book of God and Man: A Study of Job" (Box 16P, Folder 419)
    - "A Commentary on the Book of Job" by E. Dhorme, 1967 (Box 16P, Folder 420)
    - "Studies in Divine Kingshipp in the Ancient Near East" by Ivan Engell, 1967 (Box 16P, Folder 421)
    - "Oriental and Biblical Studies: Collected Writings of E.A. Speiser", 1967 (Box 16P, Folder 422)
    - "Biblischer Kommentar-Altes Testament" by Friedrich Horst, 1968 (Box 16P, Folder 423)
    - "Twentieth Century Interpretations of the Book of Job. A Collection of Critical Essays," ed. by Paul S. Sanders, 1968 (Box 16P, Folder 424)
    - "Archives from Elephantine: The Life of an Ancient Jewish Military Colony" by Bezalel Porten, 1968 (Box 16P, Folder 425)
    - "Biblischer Kommentar-Altes Testament" by Friedrich Horst, 1968 (Box 16P, Folder 426)
    - "The Violent Goddess. Anat in the Ras Shamra Texts," by Arvin S. Kapelrud, 1969 (Box 16P, Folder 427)
    - "Ugaritica VI: Tome XVII", 1969 (Box 16P, Folder 428)
    - "Die Religionen Altsyriens Altarabiens und der Mandaer", 1970 (Box 16P, Folder 429)
    - "The Book of Job. Commentary, New Translation, and Special Studies", 1979-1981 (Box 16P, Folder 430)
    - "Rank Among the Canaanite Gods, El, Baal, and the Rephaim" by Conrad E. L'Heureux, 1979 (Box 16P, Folder 431)
    - "Life and Death" by Margalit, 1981 (Box 16P, Folder 432)
    - "Ruth. A New Translation with a Philological Commentary and a Formalist-Folklorist Interpretation", 1981 (Box 16P, Folder 433)
    - "Rank Among the Canaanite Gods, El, Baal, and the Rephaim" by Conrad E. L'Heureux, 1979 (Box 16P, Folder 434)
    - "Beatific Afterlife in Ancient Israel and in the Ancient Near East", 1986 (Box 16P, Folder 435)
    - "The Song of Fourteen Songs" by D. Goulder, 1987 (Box 16P, Folder 436)
    - "Ugarit und die Bibel" by Oswald Loretz, 1990 (Box 16P, Folder 437)
    - "A Rift in the Clouds" by Marjo Christine, Annette Korpel, 1990 (Box 16P, Folder 438)
    - "The Song of Songs: A Commentary on the Book of Canticles, or the Songs of Songs" by Roland O.E. Murphy, 1992 (Box 16P, Folder 439)
    - "The Song of Songs: A Commentary on the Book of Canticles, or the Song of Songs" by Roland O.E. Murphy, 1992 (Box 16P, Folder 440)
    - "The Goddess Anat in Ugaritic Myth" by Neal H. Walls, 1992 (Box 16P, Folder 441)
    - "One Lover of Canticles Salutes Another"; "Interpretation: The Church in Transition", 1990s (Box 16P, Folder 442)
    - "Ugarit und die Bibel" by Oswald Loretz (Box 16P, Folder 443)
    - "Studies in Hebrew and Ugaritic Psalms" by Yitzhak Avishur, 1994 (Box 16P, Folder 444)
    - "Studies in Hebrew and Ugaritic Psalms" by Yitzhak Avishur, 1994 (Box 16P, Folder 445)
    - "On the Unity of the Song of Songs" by Segal, n.d. (Box 16P, Folder 446)
- Drafts/Unpublished Writings, Series IV
  - "Hosanna," for Anchor Bible Dictionary, 1992 (Box 17P, Folder 447)
  - "Hosanna", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 448)
  - "Hosanna", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 449)
  - "Hosanna, Help Please", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 450)
  - "Hosanna, Help Please!", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 451)
  - "Hosanna: Help Now (Please)", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 452)
  - "Hosanna, Help Please": 3 separate drafts, n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 453)
  - "Hosanna Means 'Help Please!' ", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 454)
  - "Hosanna Means 'Help Please' ", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 455)
  - "Hosanna--Help, Now (Please)", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 456)
  - "Hosanna-Help, Please", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 457)
  - "Hosanna---Help, Please", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 458)
  - "Hosanna: Help, Please," typed draft, n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 459)
  - "Song of Songs"; text and critique of it by David N. Freedman, notes; correspondence from Freedman re. text, 1975 (Box 17P, Folder 460)
  - coverpage of Anchor Bible Commentary on Song of Songs, n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 461)
  - correction for re-printing of Anchor Bible Series, Vol. 7C, SOS, 1970s (Box 17P, Folder 462)
  - transliteration of SOS, n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 463)
  - "Metastases in Canonical Shapes of the Super Song", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 464)
  - "Metastases in Canonical Shapes of the Super Song", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 465)
  - "Response to Sasson on the Sublime Song", 1979-1980 (Box 17P, Folder 466)
  - "Response to Sasson on the Sublime Song", 1979-1980 (Box 17P, Folder 467)
  - "Afterthoughts on SOS", 1978 (Box 17P, Folder 468)
  - ""Reasons for Supposing the Lady of the Canticle to be Superhuman", n.d. (Box 17P, Folder 469)
  - Draft re. noses and necks, SOS (Box 17P, Folder 470)
  - "Proportion in Metaphor and Simile of Solomon's Super Song, with References to Our Lady's Towering Neck and Nose", 1983 (Box 18P, Folder 471)
  - "Proportion in Metaphor and Simile of Solomon's Super Song, with References to Our Lady's Towering Neck and Nose," typed draft (Box 18P, Folder 472)
  - ""Proportion in Metaphor and Simile of Solomon's Super Song, with References to Our Lady's Towering Neck and Nose" (Box 18P, Folder 473)
  - Pope's own review of his commentary on SOS, circa 1979 (Box 18P, Folder 475)
  - Draft of a press release re. SOS commentary, n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 476)
  - "The name Job", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 477)
  - transliteration of Job, n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 478)
  - "Some Garbled Mythological Allusions in the Book of Job", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 479)
  - "The Book of Job," same lecture as that recorded on cassette; see Series VIII, 1976 (Box 18P, Folder 480)
  - "Job Still Suffers: Some Recent Treatments", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 481)
  - "Patient Job", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 482)
  - "The Word Sahat in Job 9:31", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 484)
  - "The Word Sahat in Job 9:31", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 485)
  - "New Translation of the Book of Job," Chapters 1-8, 1976-1977 (Box 18P, Folder 486)
  - "The Literary Form of the Book of Job"; "The Date of the Book of Job"; Author/Authorship", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 487)
  - "The Language of the Book of Job"; "Poetics and Prosody"; "Language and Style"; "Use of Quotations in Job" (Box 18P, Folder 488)
  - "The Place of the Book of Job in the Canon"; "Midrash, Legend, and Imitation of Job"; "Textual Problems" (Box 18P, Folder 489)
  - Draft re. Anchor Bible Series and Pope's involvement with it (Box 18P, Folder 490)
  - Pope's reflections on Gordis' study of Job and the problems it presents to scholars (Box 18P, Folder 491)
  - "West Semitic Theology and Cosmology" (Box 18P, Folder 492)
  - "Semites/Shemites", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 493)
  - "Western Semites", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 494)
  - "Hurrians", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 495)
  - "Hurrians", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 496)
  - Draft re. Abraham, Isaac, ram, and preposition ahar (Box 18P, Folder 497)
  - Draft re. evolution of English poetry as it relates to biblical poetry, n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 498)
  - "A Brief for Brevity and Pith in Translation of Biblical Poetry" (Box 18P, Folder 499)
  - "Brevity in Bible Translation", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 500)
  - "Music and Poetry" (Box 18P, Folder 501)
  - "Poetic Parallelism", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 502)
  - "Poetic Parallelisms in Biblical Poetry/Prosody", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 503)
  - "Impact of Modern Archaeology on Biblical Studies", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 504)
  - "Jezebel and Ichabod" (Box 18P, Folder 505)
  - "Dreams and Incubation" re. Hebrew Bible, Ugaritic material (Box 18P, Folder 506)
  - "Jerusalem as God's Wife", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 507)
  - Draft re. etymology of name Israel and other Hebrew names (Box 18P, Folder 508)
  - "Hybrid Maidens", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 509)
  - "Was God Circumcised?", n.d. (Box 18P, Folder 510)
  - "Notes for Holy Land Trip", 1994 April (Box 19P, Folder 511)
  - "ABGD etc.: Comments on the Origin and Evolution of the Alphabet" (Box 19P, Folder 512)
  - "Ass"; "Asses and Arses"; "Pious Punning"; draft about donkeys (Box 19P, Folder 513)
  - "The Jackass in Scripture", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 514)
  - translation, transliteration of the Babylonian Princess, Priestess YBTI, 45, n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 515)
  - "Semites Ancient and Modern," abstract (Box 19P, Folder 516)
  - "Negro"; racism, 1994 (Box 19P, Folder 517)
  - Draft re. unity of human race, Hebrew Bible, n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 518)
  - Draft re. The Holocaust as a misnomer, Yiddish, etc., n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 519)
  - "Lists and Holocausts. Who Counts?" (Box 19P, Folder 520)
  - "Lists, Holocausts, and Holy Racism" (Box 19P, Folder 521)
  - "Lists, Holocausts, and Holy Racism" (Box 19P, Folder 522)
  - "The Holocaust"; "Zion" re. Palestine, formation of Israel, n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 523)
  - "Huspa (-t) and Holy Racism" 2nd draft, typed, ca. 1995 (Box 19P, Folder 524)
  - "Huspa (-t) and Holy Racism"; "Huspa (-t)" (Box 19P, Folder 525)
  - "Huspa (-t) and Holy Racism," photocopy of original draft (Box 19P, Folder 526)
  - "Huspa (-t) and Holy Racism"; notes on holy racism (Box 19P, Folder 527)
  - "Sacred Ethnicism or Holy Racism", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 528)
  - Draft re. Schindler's List, the Holocaust; "Schindler and the Master List" (Box 19P, Folder 529)
  - "Adam, Edom, and Holocaust"; "Holocaust Before THE Holocaust" (Box 19P, Folder 530)
  - "Holocaust in the Bible", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 531)
  - "The Story of the Chinese Jews", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 532)
  - "The Background of the Palestine Situation" (Box 19P, Folder 533)
  - "Euphemism and Dysphemism" for the Anchor Bible Dictionary, 1992 (Box 19P, Folder 534)
  - "Literary Morphology", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 535)
  - "400 Year Stela", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 536)
  - "Divine Laughter and Consternation"; "Alphabet" (Box 19P, Folder 537)
  - "Purity of Arms", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 538)
  - Draft re. King David and sexual affairs in the U.S. military (Box 19P, Folder 539)
  - "Ebla"; "Alphabet, Introduction", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 540)
  - "Shibboleth," usage in Hebrew Bible and Ugaritic texts (Box 19P, Folder 541)
  - "Mixed Marriage Metaphor in Ezekiel 16," and notes (Box 19P, Folder 542)
  - "Mixed Marriage Metaphor in Ezekiel 16", n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 543)
  - "Mixed Marriage Metaphor in Ezekiel 16," photocopies, n.d. (Box 19P, Folder 544)
  - "Mixed Marriage Metaphor in Ezekiel 16" and correspondence from Fred re. draft (Box 19P, Folder 545)
  - "Mixed Metaphor in Ezekiel 16", n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 546)
  - Front page of Pope's Master of Arts Thesis on Isaiah 34 and Torrey's comments on his thesis (Box 20P, Folder 547)
  - "YHWH and His ASRT" (Box 20P, Folder 548)
  - Draft re. Biblical term rephaim, n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 549)
  - "Rephaim and Marzeah: Vital Connections" (Box 20P, Folder 550)
  - "Rephaim and Marzeah:Vital Connections", 1982 (Box 20P, Folder 551)
  - "Some Early West Semitic Prayer Formulae"; "Pastoral Prayer", n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 552)
  - "Some Early West Semitic Prayer Formulae," typed draft intended for a presentation (Box 20P, Folder 553)
  - "What's in a Name?" names in the Hebrew Bible and the ancient Near East (Box 20P, Folder 554)
  - Materials related to the lecture "Some Notes on Terminology in the Discussion of Jewish Identity", 1966 (Box 20P, Folder 555-557)
  - "Some Notes on Terminology in the Discussion of Jewish Identity," paper given at a meeting of the Ecumenical Theological Research Fraternity in Israel, 1966 Nov (Box 20P, Folder 558)
  - "Yea, A Daniel", n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 559)
  - "Adam and Edom" (Box 20P, Folder 560)
  - "Abram (Abraham and Saray)Sarah" (Box 20P, Folder 561)
  - "Laughter", n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 562)
  - ""Humor", n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 563)
  - "Scapegoats and Women" (Box 20P, Folder 564)
  - Draft re. Canaanites, Amorites and the affinity of their languages (Box 20P, Folder 565)
  - Draft re. sexuality in Hebrew Bible, language used to describe sexuality, n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 566)
  - "Help/Hero", n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 567)
  - "Dross and Glaze: Prov.26:23" (Box 20P, Folder 568)
  - Draft re. the preposition ahar, n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 569)
  - Draft re. conjuction ahar in the Bible, Genesis, Rashi, n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 570)
  - "The Timing of the Snagging of the Ram, Gen 22:13", n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 571)
  - "Hebrews and Ab/piru" (Box 20P, Folder 572)
  - "Hebrews and Habirue, Apiru" (Box 20P, Folder 573)
  - "Kissing Grain," re. Hebrew Bible, n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 574)
  - "The Kibbutz of Ditanu", n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 575)
  - Draft re. "ly" that discusses Nyberg's scholarship, n.d. (Box 20P, Folder 576)
  - "Burrows, Millar" (Box 20P, Folder 577)
  - "Community--Wider Horizons," address delivered at the Convention banquet of the North Carolina Congress of Parents and Teachers, 1962 April (Box 20P, Folder 578)
  - Draft re. Goetze memorial tribute, 1971 (Box 20P, Folder 579)
  - "The Covert Concern of Solomon's Sublime Song," Haskell Series lecture, 1977 (Box 20P, Folder 580)
  - "Love and Death: The Covert Concern of Solomon's Sublime Song," on occasion of the death of Herbert G. May (Box 20P, Folder 581)
  - "Love and Death: The Covert Concern of Solomon's Sublime Song," lecture delivered in N. Carolina (Box 20P, Folder 582)
  - Draft of a talk given at Princeton University on the subject of "Song of Songs", ca. 1978 (Box 20P, Folder 583)
  - Presentation (typed in Arabic) presented at Halb University, 1981 (Box 20P, Folder 584)
  - Talk on the subject of love and death given at a meeting of the Fellowship for Biblical Studies, 1985 Sep (Box 20P, Folder 585)
  - "The Love-Death Connection in SSS", draft of a lecture presented at College de France, 1990 May (Box 20P, Folder 586)
  - Draft of a lecture re. Marzeah given at the University of Kampen, 1990 Dec (Box 20P, Folder 587)
  - Draft re. Dead Sea Scrolls and Essenes lecture delivered at AAG, 1992 (Box 20P, Folder 588)
  - Dahood Memorial lecture at New York University, 1995 (Box 21P, Folder 589)
  - An address in English and in Hebrew given to the Israel Exploration Society (Box 21P, Folder 590)
  - Draft of a talk entitled "The Holy Mess in the Holy Land" (Box 21P, Folder 591)
  - Draft of a talk on Pope's impressions of Israel (Box 21P, Folder 592)
  - lecture/talk entitled "How Archaeological Discoveries Illuminate Bible History" (Box 21P, Folder 593)
  - MRZA lecture, n.d. (Box 21P, Folder 594)
  - Draft of a public lecture entitled "Job Still Suffers: Some Recent Treatments" (Box 21P, Folder 595)
  - Draft of talk on "Songs of songs and Sexism" (Box 21P, Folder 596)
  - Draft of "Towers, Necks, Noses, and Nonsense. Passion, Perspective and Proportion in Metaphor and Simile of Solomon's Super Song" in response to Professor Othmar Keel's lecture on the metaphorical language of the Song of Songs (Box 21P, Folder 597)
  - Draft of "Cyrus Gordon and Ugaritology," remarks for SBL Session in honor of Gordon (Box 21P, Folder 598)
  - "Ugaritic Studies: Retrospect and Prospect" delivered at SBL meeting (Box 21P, Folder 599)
  - "Love and Death at Ugarit and in the Bible," a lecture delivered at the University of Marburg (Box 21P, Folder 600)
  - "The Cult of the Dead at Ugarit," draft of a lecture (Box 21P, Folder 601)
  - "Gory Goddesses," draft of a presentation delivered at the Congress of Orientalists in N. Delhi (Box 21P, Folder 602)
  - Draft of a presentation on SOS and Ugaritic lexicography for a Ugaritic symposium (Box 21P, Folder 603)
  - index cards for Dead Sea Scrolls lecture (Box 21P, Folder 604)
  - draft for a lecture on the Dead Sea Scrolls entitled "The Dead Sea Discoveries and Their Significance" (Box 21P, Folder 605)
  - "Eros and Thanatos at Ugarit and in the Bible," draft of Mitchell Dahood lecture (Box 21P, Folder 606-607)